# Minjoo Cho

+44 7825 767135 minjoolisa.cho@gmail.com www.minjoocho.com LinkedIn

#### OBJECTIVE

I am a polymathic software designer with a solid technical background who designs and prototypes experiences that makes us better "humans".

I have over seven years of experience working within multidisciplinary design teams and have successfully turned breakthrough ideas into the broad range of tangible technical prototypes.

I want to contribute my expertise and proficiency in handling large-scale data in technically focused projects.

# SKILLS

#### **Full-stack IoT Development**

- Frontend: Web(React, Javascript/ Typescript, Flutter), Mobile (Android)
- Backend: Python-Flask, NodeJs
- Database: DynamoDB, SQLAlchemy
- Cloud Services: AWS (AWS Developer Associated certified), Google Cloud Platform
- Hardware Prototyping: Arduino, Raspberry Pi
- Messaging protocols: Messaging(web socket, MQTT), Hardware(I2C, Serial, SPI)

# **Emerging Technology**

- Machine Learning Libraries: GCP-based ML solutions (mediapipe, Polyphonic RNN etc.)
- AR/VR: Native (AR Core, Unity), Web (Playcanvas)
- Computer Vision Libraries: OpenCV, Pygame

#### **Design Tools**

- UX/UI : Figma, Protopie
- 3D (Rhinoceros, Solidworks, Fusion260, Keyshot)
- 2D Tools: Adobe Series (Illustrator, InDesign, Premier Pro)

#### LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent, C2)
- Korean (Native)
- · Japanese (Fluent, C2)
- Chinese (Intermediate, C1)
- · German (Basics, B1)

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### Senior Software Designer, D-Ford London

London, United Kingdom

June, 2021 - Present

D-Ford is an R&D lab focused on developing services, products, and visions for the future of mobility based on the human-centered design (HCD) method.

- Led and executed the development of reusable/modular prototyping platform for Ford prototyping engineers to quickly develop and deploy experiences: clibased toolkit that orchastrates containerized infrastructures with project back with git integration.
- Early-stage IoT prototyping for the initial concept validation through controlled user testing, on-site user research support

#### **Creative Technologist, Indeed Innovation**

Hamburg, Germany

May, 2017 - Apr, 2021

## Fast PoC Technical Prototyping for IoT products

- Liaison with developers and designers throughout the project's conceptual stage and helped implement proof-of-concept prototypes to validate the generated ideas.
- Client-facing role: project pitch, design workshop, development progress report Interactive Installation development/demonstration
- Full implementation of interactive installation from concept development to delivery

### **Creative Strategist, Samsung Creative Lab**

Suwon, South Korea

Jun 2013 — Oct 2014

Samsung Creative Lab is a Samsung's incubation program for Samsung employees to incubate creative ideas into actual projects. My role in the team included the following:

- Project Proposal: Proposed the winning idea to gain entry into C-Lab
- Product Strategy and development: product features definition, fast prototyping (Android SW), in charge of user research with the hearing-impaired community
- Regular progress reports to the C-level representatives

# **Product Manager, Samsung Electronics HQ**

Suwon, South Korea

Jan 2011 — Dec 2014

- Responsible for Samsung Galaxy Tablet Series and Google Nexus 10
- Product Life Cycle Management: solving procedural issues during the entire product life cycle from the development stage to the end of production
- Regular VP/C-level issue reports on the project status

#### EDUCATION

#### M.S in Industrial Design, KAIST

Daejeon, South Korea

Mar 2015 — Feb 2017

- · Mater's thesis: Calm Automaton, A DIY Toolkit for Ambient Displays
- A previous research member of <u>myDesignLAB</u> (Prof. Daniel Saakes)
- Full year scholarship: National Science and Technology Scholarship

# **B.S in Electrical Engineering, KAIST**

Daejeon, South Korea

Mar 2006 — Feb 2011

- · Major in Electrical Engineering and minor in Business Economics
- Full year scholarship: National Science and Technology Scholarship